[
  {
    "question": "Look at this series: 36, 34, 30, 28, 24, ... What number should come next?",
    "choices": ["20", "22", "23", "26"],
    "correctAnswer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Look at this series: 80, 10, 70, 15, 60, ... What number should come next?",
    "choices": ["20", "25", "30", "50"],
    "correctAnswer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "A vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?",
    "choices": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "correctAnswer": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the number would occur next in the series - 2,6,30,60,130,210",
    "choices": ["330", "350", "370", "380"],
    "correctAnswer": "350"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a part of immediate deductive inference",
    "choices": ["Conversion", "Obversion", "Syllogism", "Contraposition"],
    "correctAnswer": "Syllogism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pointing towards a man, a woman said - His wife's father is the husband of my mother's only daughter. How is the woman related to the man?",
    "choices": ["Daughter", "Sister-in-Law", "Sister", "Mother-in-Law"],
    "correctAnswer": "Mother-in-Law"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assumption of an unperceived fact in order to reconcile two apparently inconsistent perceived facts is known in Indian logic as :",
    "choices": ["Anumana (inference)", "Upamana (Comparison)", "Arthapatti (implication)", "Anupalabdhi (Non-apprehension)"],
    "correctAnswer": "Arthapatti (implication)"
  },
  {
    "question": "If income of X is 20% more than that of Y and income of Y is 25% less than that of Z, then the total income of X,Y and Z are in which of the following ratios?",
    "choices": ["18:15:20", "18:15:10", "18:10:15", "18:12:15"],
    "correctAnswer": "18:15:20"
  },
  {
    "question": " Identify the term X in the following series- 3,2,11,14,27,34,51, X",
    "choices": ["62", "69", "60", "71"],
    "correctAnswer": "62"
  },
  {
    "question": " The Smallest integer greater than 1 which is simultaneously a square and a cube of certain integers is ",
    "choices": ["8", "9", "36", "64"],
    "correctAnswer": "64"
  },
  {
    "question": "A shopkeeper sells a refrigerator for Rs 22,000 and makes a profit of 10%. If he desires to make a profit of 18%, what should be his selling price?",
    "choices": ["23,600", "29,600", "36,000", "24,600"],
    "correctAnswer": "23,600"
  },
  {
    "question": " In which of the following arguments 'the relation that exists between premises and conclusion is that of logical necessity' ?",
    "choices": ["Inductive", "Deductive", "Demonstrative", "Analogical"],
    "correctAnswer": "Deductive"
  },
  {
    "question": " If x and y are two positive numbers and x is 25% greater than y, what is the value of the ratio y/x ",
    "choices": ["0.75", "0.80", "1.20", "1.25"],
    "correctAnswer": "0.80"
  },
  {
    "question": " During one year, the population of a town increased by 5% and during the next year, the population decreased by 5%. If the total population is 29925 at the end of second year, then what was the population size in the beginning of the first year ? ",
    "choices": ["25000", "30000", "33000", "36000"],
    "correctAnswer": "30000"
  },
  {
    "question": " Consider the example - There is no jar now on the ground. Identify the means of Knowledge (pramana) ",
    "choices": ["0.75", "0.80", "1.20", "1.25"],
    "correctAnswer": "0.80"
  }
  
]
